This is the YouTube co-founder Steve Chen and I'm gonna ask him to rate my YouTube channel.
This is only what I do for a living. I'm not nervous at all.
Hold on, let's go back a little and see how it all started.
I've been making YouTube videos for years, mainly on crypto, AI, and economy.
A few weeks ago, Walden from BitGet, one of the top crypto exchanges,
texted me and asked me if I wanted to speak at a panel with the co-founder of YouTube.
I needed to get his signature, but what should I ask him to sign?
My t-shirt? Laptop? Am I husky?
I don't know. You might be wondering, why is meeting Steve such a big deal?
Well, Steve is a Taiwanese-American entrepreneur that co-founded YouTube.
He was the CTO. That means he's the one with the crazy scientist brain that came up with all the
complex tech behind YouTube. He was born in Taiwan and moved to the US at the age of 7.
He was working at PayPal when he met Chard Hurley and Javit Kareem.
In 2005, they founded YouTube. They had the vision to create the biggest video sharing platform.
Well, not quite. They wanted to create an online dating website with video.
It was to let people find their perfect match. They asked people to share videos talking about
their likes, dislikes, interests, so they could find their soulmates from the viewers as their match.
But people were a bit too shy. So the founders decided to make some changes,
and YouTube is now a cool video sharing platform. One of the co-founders, Kareem,
uploaded a video at a zoo in 2005. It was officially the first video uploaded to YouTube.
They have really, really, really long fronts, and that's cool.
Oh, and Google bought YouTube for 1.65 billion in 2006. Now, you can embed videos to other websites,
like Myspace. From there, YouTube became the biggest video sharing platform in the entire world.
It turned out, people didn't want to find their soulmates on YouTube. They were there to laugh at
funny videos. This is Ronaldinho playing soccer, the first ever video that got 1 million views.
People started making videos on how-to's, like how to be a ninja,
or how to bite your brother's finger.
You out, Charlie!
Help!
Charlie!
Here's a video of Steve's cat pajamas.
YouTube has officially reached more people than all cable TV networks combined. Want to learn how to
cook? No problem. Makeup? Yeah. How to invest? You got it. Even universities and governments are now
uploading on YouTube. 3.7 million videos are uploaded on YouTube every single day. And Mr. Beast has become
the most popular YouTuber in the world, blowing up everything he sees. Okay, let's slow down. It's time
to meet the guy who started all this. Steve was too nice to rate my channel, but he did say I'm now his
favorite YouTuber. Haha. Well, jokes aside, YouTube reshapes how an entire generation learns
and gives us the option to take control over our career choices. It's been such a wonderful journey.
Oh, and thank you, Big F, for making this happen.
This video is sponsored by Emma, the German mattress brand endorsed by the Asian superstar, Ella.
Emma has won over 75 international awards. Stay tuned for more exciting content about them later in this video.
Got the whole crypto world going wild.
Honey birthday, she's the queen of the game. Stacking crypto like it's her name to fame.
If you want success, then take a look away.
That's short and then this is like the video. Oh, you know what? Didn't I comment on your Twitter
account or something? Did you? Yeah, you got to read your tweet. Oh my god. I said I can't wait to meet.
I shouldn't be using Twitter. I should be using YouTube. Yes. Yes. Yeah. 138,000 subscribers.
How do you do that? Is that the first thing you look at? The subscribers? Number of subscribers? Yeah.
No, I have 138 without the K subscribers. It's amazing some of the people that you're...
Are these mostly interviews? Interviews and sometimes big news in crypto.
Well, it's an honor to meet. I'm still so new to this, so this could be educational for me.
No, you're not. I'm like eight weeks into crypto. How did you get into crypto?
Video itself was uploaded 19 years ago, but all of a sudden, about six, seven weeks ago on Twitter,
I just started receiving hundreds and hundreds of tweets referencing me in pajamas, the name of the cat.
And you'll see from the video, it's got 400,000 views. It doesn't have a lot of views. And so
suddenly, a thousand tweets come in. And that's when I started asking some of my own friends in
Silicon Valley, mostly that I've invested in in the web through world, like, what is going on here?
Like, why are they all... And then there's... I saw people started actually sharing the deck screen or
like a website and they started showing me the prices. And I'm like, what are they trying to buy?
Are they trying to buy the video? Because I can't just give a video away on YouTube, right?
Are they trying to buy the cat? Because the cat's, I mean, 19 years ago video, I mean, it's no longer in
this world. So what are they trying to buy? And it took like, probably like 35 minutes of explanation
before. Like, this is completely just like decentralized, like completely just buying tokens
that somehow correlate to... It took a while, but of course, I was curious. And so I went and bought
some. Wow, okay. But it takes a long time. I think that's a problem with the, I think these
decentralized exchanges, all these different apps that you had to download and all these 12 word
keys that you have to write down and phrases. And, and I had like a ledger and all this stuff. And
I'm like, finally, I get it. But it goes from like $9,000 to like $50,000 in like two hours.
So I was like, well, there's maybe something more to this. So I mean, that was the story of how it all
got started to compress into like, half a day. I think the original guides that created have long,
long, long left. And I think it's one of these few tokens where it ends up being just completely
community driven 100%. And, and everything, I mean, just from spending time on telegram, like for 10
hours a day with like the, I didn't, I hadn't even had, I had to download telegram.
Right. And then after that, now it's like my most used app just talking with, you know,
six, 7,000 people that's on the network and learning more about the community and differences between
web two and web three. And there are, there are some similarities, but definitely some differences.
Like, uh, uh, they were so surprised that I was showing my face, uh, because people don't show
their faces in web three. People don't tell them like their real names in web three, but it's cool.
And we have a community, uh, even somebody that flew out just for tonight's event. Uh, when I was
back in San Francisco last week, I had somebody from LA that was part of the community also fly up.
And so, I mean, I think it's just kind of a combination between web two and web three.
That's pretty exciting to me, to be frank, like pajamas, to me, it's not going to be the returns that
like an investment in a Silicon Valley company is going to get actually still involved a lot with
Silicon Valley, a lot of investments still, but here in Taiwan, I think what's exciting is like,
there's a lot of opportunities for entrepreneurs and for startups here in Taiwan that want to make
it out of the global stage. So, so trying to act as kind of that bridge between, you know, Taiwan,
because I'm physically present here, the entrepreneurs, the ideas, they're there here as well.
I think the more difficult, more challenging part here versus say, San Francisco is trying to find funding.
Early stage funding, like risk taking funding. I think a lot of the
VC firms here, they don't like to take that risk, but we can make those connections happen.
Right. And if that happens, I think that's great for Taiwan and for Silicon Valley.
Do you think the education in Taiwan makes it very hard to be an entrepreneur?
I think it does have an impact, but I want to say like, there are definitely pockets of people
that are TIDA graduates that are the top GPA, but are actually entrepreneurial minded.
I, when I first moved here, I kept thinking that I'm not going to invest in any of these
companies that are started by Taiwanese entrepreneurs, but I've started to make investments in Taiwanese
entrepreneurs. They have to start thinking globally from day one, like they have to start thinking,
like version one of the app needs to be in English. It can't just be in Chinese in Taiwan.
And if it's successful, then we'd launch a V2 in English, like that's too late.
Okay.
But like some of these entrepreneurs from TIDA, like, I mean, they're, they're English is flawless.
They understand the, uh, the capital markets outside of Taiwan. And so they can come up with
products that are usable from the global side of things. They won. It's still a little early to tell,
but I have written some checks to just like really Taiwanese startups that are based in Taiwan,
but are focused for the entire world in terms of their audience.
They hit the lottery when you're on board, but you can't, you can't top YouTube, right?
Well, yeah.
Are you still studying like the trends of YouTube and how they change to shorts, long form and all that?
I think YouTube shorts and Tik Tok and a lot of Instagram relative to those videos, those are
going to be catered towards like just the shorter attention spans of many users on the internet today,
especially the younger audiences. Right. But I, I guess, uh, you know, you just need to cater to
whatever your audience wants. Do you watch Mr. Beast?
Not really. Not really. Okay. Um, who's your all time favorite YouTuber? Is there like a OG YouTuber?
Mostly what I'm using YouTube for, like if you see my recommendations, there'll be things that are
like camera equipment reviews or electronic reviews, which it's great for that purpose.
Maybe music videos or something. If you were to ask me like, we're the top five YouTubers that,
you know, like I wouldn't, of course you. Oh my God.
And Mr. Beast. I don't know who the other, it's embarrassing, but. But everyone, everyone knows you.
So, uh, subscribe to my channel with 400 people subscribing. Subscribe.
Last thing. Can I ask you to rate my thumbnail? I made this little thing.
Oh, I made my thumbnail from one to 10.
Actually, what is this thing? There was like this report showing that Taiwanese are very rich.
Yeah, but I mean, a lot of people don't think so. So it's like controversial.
Yeah. And this one is Jensen Huang. Well, it's a huge thing. I mean, to be honest,
like Taiwanese Americans in Silicon Valley are doing very, very well, right? I mean, uh, someone that's
come back here with me, um, Kevin Lin from Twitch, um, you've got AMD, Nvidia, like Lisa Su, like,
there's a lot of Taiwanese Americans there. I think like, it'd be great to be able to bring back some of that.
It's either like 9.9 or 10. Come on. Okay.
10. Look at that. Come on, 10 again.
I'm going to put this on my wall, guys. Could you sign this for me?
Oh, no way. Yes, please.
This is the first time I'm holding one of these.
No way. That's cool. No, I've never held, I've never held one of these before.
This is the first time I've ever actually seen this.
I mean, I've seen it because a lot of the YouTubers, they have it on there, like, um,
like studios and stuff, but do you have your next one, the more million subscribers?
No, I will try.
All right. It's going to be in English.
Oh my God.
Well, thank you so much.
Hello.
How was the money?
But the niche followers at $9,000, but it's $50,000.
I'm going to go.
Whether I'm creating YouTube videos or deep and investment research,
productivity boosting products are crucial.
And speaking of that, here's a quick note about our sponsor today.
Emma, Europe's top mattress seller has sold over 7 million mattresses worldwide.
Impressive, right?
Emma's diamond degree tech keeps you cool in summer and cozy in winter.
40% more breathable than regular memory foam.
It absorbs body heat, improving temperature control by 23%.
It combines pocket springs and six memory foam layers for strong support and pressure relief,
keeping your spine aligned and reducing back pain.
Perfect for sharing with partners, family, or pets without disturbance.
The washable outer cover and handles make it easy to maintain and move.
Shipped rolled up and vacuum sealed.
It's easy for one to two people to assemble.
Ideal for renters.
Pairing with the diamond memory pillow is extra comfortable.
Featuring graphene infused cotton for a cool breathable feel.
I like my pillows high.
This is adjustable for height and firmness.
Made from 100% natural bamboo fiber, fights bacteria, and filled with lightweight breathable fibers.
Easy machine wash-ins for freshness.
The black diamond mattress is perfect for the weather.
Soft, yet supportive.
Bye-bye backaches.
For summer deals starting at 45% off, visit the link in the description or use promo code
SLEEPTW10 for an exclusive 10% off all items.
Combine discounts for greater savings.
Plus, enjoy a 100-day trial, 10-year warranty, and free delivery installation across Taiwan.
Keep pushing forward.
Thank you for watching this video.
Subscribe for more content like this.
And I hope you'll see you again soon.
Thank you.
歡迎用下面的連結到LINE跟Discord群組
跟努力的大家一起討論
我們在OKAXBN派網跟其他大交易所
都幫大家爭取到了最高8折20%OFF的交易手續費減免
用下面的連結註冊呢
你的交易成本就更低了
也歡迎告訴我你接下來想要看什麼
我們在帝圈繼續努力
下次見 掰掰